<title>FSCode Formatting</title>

<macro:toc align="right" inline="no"/>

<h level="1">Tags</h>

<i>Tags</i> are how you specify text formatting in FSCode-enabled contexts.  FSCode is an HTML-like markup that supports more tags, more styles, and more features.  It also supports some <i>macros</i> which can automate a large amount of formatting and organizational typesetting work.  For instance, the table of contents for this page was automatically generated by a macro.

FSCode bears more similarity to typesetting software such as TeX or WikiSyntax.  What you type is interpreted to generate another kind of document which will display more advanced features.  You would use FSCode to write a document, and then later (or concurrently) tweak the output to adjust the display.  This ensures that all the formatting throughout the document is consistent.  If you are using FSCode as part of a web site then you probably have no control over the display - FSCode will still allow you a massive degree of flexibility in how you author content while keeping it aesthetically coordinated with the rest of the site.

<i>Anatomy of a Tag</i>

All tags have several things in common.  Firstly, they are all began with a less-than character (&lt;).  They all have a name, and they all close with a greater-than character (&gt;).  Tags that are unrecognized are ignored and will appear in the final product without any textual differences.  If you want to "escape" a tag (instruct FSCode to ignore it) then you should use the HTML character instructions &amp;lt; for the less-than character &lt; and &amp;gt; for the greater-than character &gt;.

Most tags also require a closing tag.  These closing tag uses a forward-slash (/) before the tag name, and is otherwise identical to any other tag.

A few example tags are given:

<table align="center">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;b&gt;bold text&lt;/b&gt;</cell>
		<cell><b>bold text</b></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;i&gt;italicized text&lt;/i&gt;</cell>
		<cell><i>italicized text</i></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h1>Basic Formatting Tags</h1>

<macro:toc align="right" inline="no" start-depth="1"/>

<h2>Bold Text</h2>

Bolded text is done using the <code>b</code> tag.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;b&gt;bold text&lt;/b&gt;</cell>
		<cell><b>bold text</b></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h2>Italicized Text</h2>

Italicized text is done using the <code>i</code> tag.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;i&gt;italicized text&lt;/i&gt;</cell>
		<cell><i>italicized text</i></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h2>Underlined Text</h2>

Underlined text is done using the <code>u</code> tag.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;u&gt;underlined text&lt;/u&gt;</cell>
		<cell><u>underlined text</u></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h2>Superscripted Text</h2>

Superscripted text is done using the <code>super</code> tag.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;i&gt;e&lt;/i&gt;&lt;super&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/super&gt;</cell>
		<cell><i>e</i><super><i>x</i></super></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h2>Subscripted Text</h2>

Subscripted text is done using the <code>sub</code> tag.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;'&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;(&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;) = &lt;i&gt;ku&lt;/i&gt;(&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;)</cell>
		<cell><i>f</i>'<sub>5</sub>(<i>x</i>) = <i>ku</i>'(<i>x</i>)</cell>
	</row>
</table>

<i>assuming that f</i>(<i>x</i>) = <i>ku</i>(<i>x</i>) <i>such that</i> k <i> is a constant and u</i>(<i>x</i>) <i>is a differentiable function.</i>

<h2>Code Text</h2>

The <code>code</code> tag is used to make text monospaced.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;code&gt;public static void main&lt;/code&gt;</cell>
		<cell><code>public static void main</code></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h2>Preformatted Text</h2>

Preformatted text is a good way to completely escape any and all formatting.  It also makes the output monospace (like the <code>code</code> tag) and additionally it preserves the linebreaks.  Unfortunately it cannot uniformly guarantee the status of the line wrapping, so variance may occur between different emission mediums.

<table align="left">
	<row>
		<cell><center>Tag</center></cell>
		<cell><center>Generated Text</center></cell>
	</row>
	<row>
		<cell>&lt;pre&gt;text, pure and unadulterated&lt;/pre&gt;</cell>
		<cell><pre>text, pure and unadulterated</pre></cell>
	</row>
</table>

<h2>Paragraph Breaks</h2>

In order to start a new paragraph, use two line returns (hit enter two times).

<h1>More Complex Tags</h1>

These tags make use of definable attributes or are otherwise related to each other.  They offer more powerful formatting, but are more difficult to use.

<h2>Heading Tags</h2>

Heading tags are used to make text larger and like a section or chapter header.  They also relay information to the table of contents macro, so they facilitate the automatic generation of a table of contents that you can insert anywhere in the document.

There are six defined heading tags, though you can use an abstracted tag to go still further (or if you dislike the more compact named tags for some reason).

<table align="right">
	<row><cell>&lt;h1&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;</cell></row>
	<row><cell>&lt;h2&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;</cell></row>
	<row><cell>&lt;h3&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;</cell></row>
	<row><cell>&lt;h4&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;</cell></row>
	<row><cell>&lt;h5&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;</cell></row>
	<row><cell>&lt;h6&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;</cell></row>
	<row><cell>&lt;h level="#"&gt;Heading #&lt;/h&gt;</cell></row>
</table>

<h2>Manual Breaks</h2>

You can break a paragraph at any time using a <code>br</code> tag.  This tag supports an option to perform an object-break, which will cause the text to continue below an object that wraps to the left or right of text.  To illustrate this:

<b>Before</b>:

<img align="left" src="http://www.example.com/img.jpg"/>Talk about the image here.

Moving on, we're talking about something else but we're still associated with the image to the left.

<br wrap="object"/>

<b>After</b>:

<img align="left" src="http://www.example.com/img.jpg"/>Talk about the image here.
<br wrap="object"/>
Moving on, we're talking about something else and we're not longer associated with the image above.

<br wrap="object"/>

<b>Code</b>:

&lt;b&gt;Before&lt;/b&gt;:

&lt;img align="left" src="http://www.example.com/img.jpg"/&gt;Talk about the image here.

Moving on, we're talking about something else but we're still associated with the image on the left.

&lt;br wrap="object"/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;After&lt;/b&gt;:

&lt;img align="left" src="http://www.example.com/img.jpg"/&gt;Talk about the image here.&lt;br wrap="object"/&gt;

Moving on, we're talking about something else but we're still associated with the image on the left.

&lt;br wrap="object"/&gt;